{
	"questions": [
	{
		"question": "Who won the UEFA European Championship of 2000?",
		"correctAnswer": "France",
		"wrongAnswers": "Italy\r\nPortugal\r\nSpain"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What word means “zero” when calling the score in tennis?",
		"correctAnswer": "Love",
		"wrongAnswers": "Dove\r\nNothing\r\nHug"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What sport doesn’t have a goalie position?",
		"correctAnswer": "Basketball",
		"wrongAnswers": "Ice Hockey\r\nSoccer\r\nLacrosse"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What is the center of an atom called?",
		"correctAnswer": "Nucleus",
		"wrongAnswers": "DNA\r\nMolecule\r\nCell"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What is the unit of measure for sound?",
		"correctAnswer": "Decibels",
		"wrongAnswers": "Photons\r\nAudibles\r\nElectrons"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Which element is Ra in the periodic table?",
		"correctAnswer": "Radium",
		"wrongAnswers": "Rubidium\r\nRadio\r\nRhodium"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What is the charge of a proton?",
		"correctAnswer": "+1",
		"wrongAnswers": "-1\r\n0\r\n+2"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Where is the Nile river?",
		"correctAnswer": "Africa",
		"wrongAnswers": "America\r\nEurope\r\nAsia"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Which city is not in Germany?",
		"correctAnswer": "Bern",
		"wrongAnswers": "Duesseldorf\r\nMunich\r\nFreiburg"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Who is on the hundred dollar bill?",
		"correctAnswer": "Benjamin Franklin",
		"wrongAnswers": "Thomas Jefferson\r\nGeorge Washington\r\nRobert E Lee"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What inspired Walt Disney to make Disney?",
		"correctAnswer": "A Mouse",
		"wrongAnswers": "A Bird\r\nA Dog\r\nA Rat"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What culture thought of cats as gods?",
		"correctAnswer": "Egyptians",
		"wrongAnswers": "Germans\r\nSaudi Arabians\r\nFrench"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Who fought Medusa?",
		"correctAnswer": "Perseus",
		"wrongAnswers": "Theseus\r\nAchilles\r\nHercules"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What is the largest art museum in the world?",
		"correctAnswer": "The Louvre",
		"wrongAnswers": "New York Museum Of Art\r\nMusee D’orsay\r\nThe National Gallery"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Which of these is a Brazilian Painter?",
		"correctAnswer": "Romero Britto",
		"wrongAnswers": "Picasso\r\nMichaelangelo\r\nLeonardo Da Vinci"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What is one of the noble gases?",
		"correctAnswer": "Helium (He)",
		"wrongAnswers": "Chlorine (Cl)\r\nLithium (Li)\r\nCarbon (C)"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What is Lara Croft training with\r\nin the opening scene of ‘Tomb Raider’?",
		"correctAnswer": "With a robot",
		"wrongAnswers": "With 3D glasses\r\nWith a tiger\r\nWith a martial arts master"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "With what colour flame does sodium burn when heated\r\nin the flame of a Bunsen burner?",
		"correctAnswer": "Yellow",
		"wrongAnswers": "Violet\r\nRed\r\nGreen"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Which island is in Africa?",
		"correctAnswer": "Madagascar",
		"wrongAnswers": "Tortuga\r\nIsle of Man\r\nCyprus"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Why do crocodiles leave their mouth open for a long time?",
		"correctAnswer": "To stay warm",
		"wrongAnswers": "To drink water\r\nTo digest food\r\nTo wait for an\nanimal to drop in"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Why is The Dead Sea called that way?",
		"correctAnswer": "Because nothing can live in it",
		"wrongAnswers": "It rhymes with The Red Sea\r\nBodies are buried\nat the bottom\r\nBecause of a\nhistorical war"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Whose quote is “Fly like a butterfly sting like a bee”?",
		"correctAnswer": "Muhammad Ali",
		"wrongAnswers": "Usain Bolt\r\nTyson Gay\r\nGandhi"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Who’s the writer of ‘Game of Thrones’?",
		"correctAnswer": "George R.R. Martin",
		"wrongAnswers": "J.K. Rowling\r\nCamila Lackberg\r\nKen Follett"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Who’s the father of modern electromagnetism?",
		"correctAnswer": "Maxwell",
		"wrongAnswers": "Faraday\r\nHelmoltz\r\nVolta"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Who’s the author of ‘The Picture of Dorian Gray’?",
		"correctAnswer": "Oscar Wilde",
		"wrongAnswers": "Arthur Conan Doyle\r\nGeorge Orwell\r\nCharles Dickens"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Who’s the author of ‘Moby Dick’?",
		"correctAnswer": "Herman Melville",
		"wrongAnswers": "Ralph Waldo Emerson\r\nHenry James\r\nHenry David Thoreau"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Who’s the artist of the famous painting ‘The Sunflowers’?",
		"correctAnswer": "Van Gogh",
		"wrongAnswers": "Monet\r\nRembrandt\r\nGoya"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "The Half Life symbol is what Greek letter?",
		"correctAnswer": "Lambda",
		"wrongAnswers": "Omicron\r\nSigma\r\nOmega"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Which of these is not one of Rockstar Games' hits,\r\nbut is actually a puzzle-platformer developed by Valve?",
		"correctAnswer": "Portal",
		"wrongAnswers": "L.A. Noire\r\nRed Dead Redemption\r\nGrand Theft Auto V"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What fruit is most commonly used to make wine?",
		"correctAnswer": "Grape",
		"wrongAnswers": "Strawberries\r\nApples\r\nPears"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "How many wings does a bee have?",
		"correctAnswer": "4",
		"wrongAnswers": "2\r\n6\r\n8"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What is irregular about the Manx cat?",
		"correctAnswer": "No tail",
		"wrongAnswers": "No fur\r\nNo pointy ears\r\nClear irises"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "The siege of which city is described in Homer's Iliad?",
		"correctAnswer": "Troy",
		"wrongAnswers": "Crete\r\nAthens\r\nIthaca"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "How long does it take light from the Sun to\r\nreach the Earth?",
		"correctAnswer": "8 minutes 20 seconds",
		"wrongAnswers": "5 minues 40 seconds\r\n2 minutes 20 seconds\r\n10 minutes 10 seconds"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "What Country was first to be able to buy the CD?",
		"correctAnswer": "Japan",
		"wrongAnswers": "China\r\nUSA\r\nGermany"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "How many squares make up a standard 'Snakes & Ladders' board?",
		"correctAnswer": "100",
		"wrongAnswers": "50\r\n80\r\n60"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Ailurophobia is a fear of what?",
		"correctAnswer": "Cats",
		"wrongAnswers": "Dogs\r\nHorses\r\nBirds"
	  },
	  {
		"question": "Pediophobia is a fear of what?",
		"correctAnswer": "Dolls",
		"wrongAnswers": "Kids\r\nThe Pope\r\nReptiles"
	  },
  {
    "question": "'The Stand' is a book written by which author?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stephen King",
    "wrongAnswers": "Dean Koontz\r\nRichard Laymon\r\nRay Bradbury"
  },
  {
    "question": "'Watchers' is a book written by which author?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dean Koontz",
    "wrongAnswers": "Agatha Christie\r\nDan Brown\r\nNeil Gaiman"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cartoon TV characters catchphrase is \"D'oh!\"?",
    "correctAnswer": "Homer Simpson",
    "wrongAnswers": "Peter Griffin\r\nHank Hill\r\nArcher\r\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pele was a famous footballer who was born in which country?",
    "correctAnswer": "Brazil",
    "wrongAnswers": "Argentina\r\nColumbia\r\nChile"
  },
  {
    "question": "George Best was a famous footballer who was born in which country? ",
    "correctAnswer": "Northern Ireland",
    "wrongAnswers": "Scotland\r\nEngland\r\nWales"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a male swan known as?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cob",
    "wrongAnswers": "Bob\r\nFob\r\nLob"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many years did Nelson Mandela spend in prison?",
    "correctAnswer": "27",
    "wrongAnswers": "17\r\n7\r\n37"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the television acronym HDMI stand for?",
    "correctAnswer": "High Definition\rMultimedia Interface",
    "wrongAnswers": "High Definition\nMulti Incorporated\r\nHigh Definition\nMusic Interferance\r\nHigh Definition\nMultiple Integration\r\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Herpetology is the study of what?",
    "correctAnswer": "Reptiles",
    "wrongAnswers": "Amphibians\r\nBirds\r\nTrees"
  },
  {
    "question": "An 'Oryx' is what kind of animal?",
    "correctAnswer": "Antelope",
    "wrongAnswers": "Crocodile\r\nLeopard\r\nGiraffe"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 'mazard' is a type of which fruit?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cherry",
    "wrongAnswers": "Pineapple\r\nMango\r\nStrawberry\r\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "What colour is an amethyst?",
    "correctAnswer": "Purple",
    "wrongAnswers": "Amber\r\nTurquoise\r\nGold\r\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Budgerigars are native to which country?",
    "correctAnswer": "Australia",
    "wrongAnswers": "New Zealand\r\nThailand\r\nArgentina"
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did Fidel Castro become president of Cuba?",
    "correctAnswer": "1976",
    "wrongAnswers": "1970\r\n1972\r\n1978"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was Elvis Presley born?",
    "correctAnswer": "1935",
    "wrongAnswers": "1933\r\n1930\r\n1940"
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was the piano invented?",
    "correctAnswer": "1709",
    "wrongAnswers": "1609\r\n1509\r\n1809"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal, when born, averages between 6 to 8 metres long?",
    "correctAnswer": "Blue Whale",
    "wrongAnswers": "African Rhino\r\nHippopotomaus\r\nAnaconda\r\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country, during World War 2,\r\nwas 'The Battle of El Alamein' fought?",
    "correctAnswer": "Egypt",
    "wrongAnswers": "Cyprus\r\nGreece\r\nTurkey"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country would you find the city of 'Ghent'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Belgium",
    "wrongAnswers": "Holland\r\nGermany\r\nPoland"
  },
  {
    "question": "'The Wall Street Crash' happened in which year?",
    "correctAnswer": "1929",
    "wrongAnswers": "1939\r\n1919\r\n1949"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where would you find a grasshoppers ears?",
    "correctAnswer": "On its legs",
    "wrongAnswers": "On its forehead\r\nOn its back\r\nOn its stomach"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where in Britain would you find the River Medina?",
    "correctAnswer": "Isle of Wight",
    "wrongAnswers": "Isle of Man\r\nNorthern Ireland\r\nWales"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the piece of wood called that is the traditional\r\ncentrepiece of a fire in the hearth at Christmas?",
    "correctAnswer": "Yule Log",
    "wrongAnswers": "Yale Log\r\nBule Log\r\nFool Log"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which English football team play\r\nat Kingston Communications Stadium?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hull City",
    "wrongAnswers": "Birmingham City\r\nStoke City\r\nManchester City"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what event did eight London policemen\r\nwin gold medals in the 1908 Olympics?",
    "correctAnswer": "Tug of War",
    "wrongAnswers": "Discus\r\nHammer Throw\r\nHigh Jump\r\n"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group had a top ten hit in 1981 with Romeo And Juliet?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dire Straits",
    "wrongAnswers": "U2\r\nDeacon Blue\r\nMadness"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Bruce Willis use to\r\ndestroy an aeroplane in Die Hard 2?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cigarette lighter",
    "wrongAnswers": "His fists\r\nMobile phone\r\nCutlery"
  },
  {
    "question": " What unusual accident led to the injuries which\r\ncaused Portuguese dictator Salazar's death?",
    "correctAnswer": "His deck\rchair collapsed",
    "wrongAnswers": "He was burned\rwhile cooking eggs\r\nTripped over\rtied shoelaces\r\nSuffered shock\rafter a balloon popped"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fairground attraction was first\r\npatented by Edwin Prescott in 1898?",
    "correctAnswer": "Roller coaster",
    "wrongAnswers": "Haunted house\r\nStrongman hammer & bell\r\nSpinning teacups"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Cliff Richard's backing group\r\ncalled before they became The Shadows?",
    "correctAnswer": "Drifters",
    "wrongAnswers": "Sifters\r\nWifters\r\nLifters"
  },
  {
    "question": "A negus is a hot drink made from lemon\r\njuice and what alcoholic ingredient?",
    "correctAnswer": "Port",
    "wrongAnswers": "Gin\r\nBrandy\r\nWhiskey"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many films did Laurel and Hardy make?",
    "correctAnswer": "117",
    "wrongAnswers": "100\r\n124\r\n250"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many holes are there in a ten pin bowling ball?",
    "correctAnswer": "Three",
    "wrongAnswers": "Two\r\nFive\r\nFour"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the only mammal with four knees?",
    "correctAnswer": "Elephant",
    "wrongAnswers": "Dog\r\nCheetah\r\nRhino"
  },
  {
    "question": "In The Wizard of Oz what is the name of Dorothy's dog?",
    "correctAnswer": "Toto",
    "wrongAnswers": "Lolo\r\nTito\r\nLato"
  }
	]
}